We now interrupt with breaking news.
现在插播一条最新消息
Ling Dong from Class 5, Grade 11
高二五班的凌冬同学
will represent Chenjun High School
将代表辰郡高中
once again in competition.
再次出征
He will be participating
他将报名参加
in the city talent competition.
市才艺大赛的节目选拔
It sounds like Lan Jinghui.
这是兰靖灰的声音
Ling Dong,
凌冬
how did you end up
你怎么又和兰靖灰
getting involved with Lan Jinghui?
混在一起了
Sir,
老师
I need to go to the restroom.
我想去一下洗手间
I'll be right back.
马上就回来
Go ahead.
去吧
Ling Dong.
凌冬
Let's continue.
来 我们接着来
Chen Luyang,
陈璐阳
didn't you say you solved it too?
你不说也做出来了吗
Yes.
是 老师
OK, explain to us.
来 你来讲讲
OK.
好
Guys.
同学们
The vigor of youth,
青春的活力
the fervor of youth,
青春的激情
will be fully manifested
将在你的身上
through you.
尽情地体现
Embrace and challenge yourself.
迎接自我 挑战自我
We have faith that you will succeed.
我们相信你一定能行
Ling Dong,
凌冬同学
unleash your vitality.
尽情释放你的活力吧
We're rooting for you,
我们为你呐喊
proud of you.
为你自豪
Hey.
来了
How could I not show up
大外甥这么想引起
when my nephew is trying so hard
二表舅的注意
to get my attention?
我能不来吗
You had to withdraw
你之前是因为要参加
from the talent competition
物理竞赛
to participate in the physics competition.
所以退出了才艺大赛
I was fine with that.
我都不说什么了
Now that the physics competition is over,
现在你比完了
surely you can go to this one, right?
你总能参加了吧
I don't get it.
我就不懂了
Why are you so keen on me?
怎么这么想让我参加
Do you want to see me every day?
是想天天就看见我吗
Isn't that annoying?
烦不烦啊
I'm the one who's annoyed with you, OK?
我才烦你呢 好吗
I don't care.
我不管啊
The whole school has heard
现在全校都已经听见了
that you are going to
你
compete in the talent competition.
要参加才艺大赛的比赛
If you back out now,
如果你还退出
you'll be a coward.
那你就是缩头乌龟
Alright, step aside.
行 你让一让
What are you doing?
干什么
I'm going to tell the entire school
我要向全校宣布
that you're my nephew.
你是我的大外甥
Lan Jinghui,
兰靖灰
what tricks are you playing now?
你又要干什么啊
Mr. Zhang.
主任好
Hello.
好
Mr. Zhang, what brings you here?
主任 你怎么来了
Why am I here?
我怎么来了
If I didn't come, you'd bring destruction.
我要再不来你就上天了
This is the broadcast room,
这是学校的广播站
not your playground.
不是你胡闹的地方
Go and run some laps.
跑圈去
What about him?
不 那他呢
And you...
还有
Ling Dong,
凌冬
I've told you many times.
我跟你说了好多遍了
I left Lan Jinghui in your care
我把兰靖灰交给你
to make sure
就是为了让你
he could behave himself.
好好地管住他对不对
You can't let him have his way.
不能由着他性子来
I got it, sir.
我知道了 主任
Go back to class.
上课去吧
See you Mr. Zhang.
主任再见
See ya.
再见
Just go.
去吧
What the...
不 不是
Hey, Mr. Zhang,
不是 不是 主任
this is preferential treatment, isn't it?
这差别对待也太大了吧
Go on, start running laps.
跑圈去
I...
我
Holy mother of god.
哎哟我的天
Xiaohua.
小画
Ling Dong.
凌冬
Sorry.
对不起
If I hadn't
如果当初
withdrawn from the talent competition,
不是我退出才艺大赛
you wouldn't be in...
你现在也不会
It's fine, Ling Dong.
没事 没事 凌冬
Honestly.
真的
We're doing great.
我们现在挺好的
We've put in a lot of effort.
我们可努力了
So...
那个
If you're not too busy,
你要是没事的话
you could come and watch us practice.
你也可以看我们排练啊
We're not quite there yet,
虽然我们现在还不太好
but...
但是
Would you come and watch us?
你会来吗
♪A pot of cloudy wine brings fleeting joy,♪
一壶浊酒尽余欢
♪tonight, let's forget the chill in our dreams.♪
今宵别梦寒
Have some water.
喝口热水吧
Thanks.
谢谢
Is it still pretty bad?
我是不是唱得还是不好
No, you're doing well, I think.
没有啊 我觉得很不错
Really?
真的吗
Absolutely.
当然
You could still improve.
还是有提升的空间
Ling Dong.
凌冬
What are you doing here?
你在干什么呢
Are you doing your
是不是又给我来这儿
mind-tricks again?
蛊惑人心了
Ling Dong came to see our practice.
凌冬是来看我们排练的
He thinks I did really good.
他说我唱得很不错
Ignore his blabber.
你别听他胡说
Well, not all of it is blabber.
当然了 也不全是胡说
You've got potential,
还是可圈可点的
and there's plenty of room to improve.
而且有很大的提升空间
If I'm still not good enough now,
我要是现在这样的话
what if I screw up on stage
到时候上台演出
during the competition?
还是唱不好怎么办
That won't happen.
不会
As your master, I give you my word.
你师父我跟你保证
You'll be fine.
绝对没问题
His pinky is over his thumb.
他小拇指竟然在大拇指上面
I guarantee it!
真的 真的 真的
Lan Jinghui,
兰靖灰
your hand was...
你刚才手
What about it?
我手怎么了
My hand's fine.
我手好得很
Be gone!
去 消失
Get out now.
立马消失
You've overstayed.
差不多待够了
Enough is enough.
可以了
Don't interrupt our practice.
别打扰我们排练
I swear
我保证
to always be your friend.
永远做你的好朋友
Now, you should swear too.
来 你也保证
That's not how it's done.
你这样不对
I can't do that.
我做不到
Watch me do it.
你看我可以
Off with you.
去去去
Lost in thoughts of space, are you?
神游太空呢你
Since when did you become so attentive?
什么时候这么关心我了
You even know I'm fond of space.
还知道我喜欢太空呢
Who's attentive to you?
谁关心你了
It was just a casual question, alright?
我就是随口一问好吗
A casual question that's quite telling.
随口一问就这么清楚
What does it mean?
说明什么
It means, my dear nephew,
说明大外甥
you're getting to know your uncle.
越来越懂二表舅了
I'm here to study. That's quite something.
我肯来自习就不错了
Don't push it.
你别给我得寸进尺
Whether I push it or not,
我会不会得寸进尺
will depend on your effort.
那就要看你表现了
What's this?
这什么
Can't you read?
不识字啊
A middle school workbook?
初中练习册
Are you mocking my intelligence?
你侮辱我智商呢
I simply selected exercises
我只是根据你的水平
that match your level.
选择合适你的习题而已
I've realized you
我发现你这个人
truly have a double standard.
是真双标啊
What's this "selected exercises"
什么叫根据我的水平
"that match my level?"
帮我选择的初中练习册
And I have to work through it?
我还要做
I signed you up for the talent contest
那我根据你的水平帮你
that I thought suits your level.
报名的才艺大赛
Why aren't you participating?
你为什么不参加呢
Alright then.
那好啊
If you can complete these exercises
只要你能做完这套习题
with an error rate
而且容错率
under one percent,
在百分之一以内
then you can count me in.
我就参加
And you will even join our band?
并且加入我们乐队
Sure.
确实
Just...
这
just like that?
这么 这么痛快的吗
But remember, you have to finish
但是前提是你要做完
with an error rate
并且容错率
under one percent.
百分之一以内
You're not playing tricks, are you?
不会有诈吧
So you're saying
那你的意思就是说
I can only afford one mistake?
我只能错一道
What's the matter?
怎么
Think you'd fail?
觉得自己做不到啊
I can definitely pull it off.
我保证能做到
Good.
好
Then it's a deal.
行 那我们就成交了啊
Deal.
成交
May your wish come true,
祝你心想事成
my dear nephew.
大外甥
Ling Dong, this time
凌冬 你这次
you're definitely going to lose the bet.
肯定得栽在我手上
Once you're in the band,
到了乐队
I'll show you what I can do.
你看我怎么整你
Is this supposed to be middle school math?
这是初中的数学题吗
It's ridiculously hard.
这也太难了
If you peek at the answers, the deal's off.
查答案的话 交易作废
Did he put up cameras or something?
装监控了吧
How would he know if I checked online?
他怎么知道我看
Young man, uphold your integrity.
年轻人讲武德
I can do this on my own.
小爷我靠自己
Alright.
行
Ling Dong, just you wait.
凌冬 你给我等着
Even on my own,
我就算是靠自己
I'll manage to pull this off.
我也能整到你
These middle school problems
你给我这几道初中的题
are piece of cake.
实在是太简单了
Just 10 minutes.
十分钟
All done.
搞定
So this is why you asked me to come to
所以这就是你大晚上
school in the middle of the night.
把我叫到学校的原因啊
A promise is a promise, after all.
承诺在先嘛
Some people have a track record
这毕竟有的人
of being untrustworthy.
有前科 不太值得信任
You're not scared,
我看你该不会是
are you?
害怕了吧
After all, maintaining
毕竟百分之一的容错率
an error rate of one percent
对于你来说
is no easy task for you.
不是件容易事
That's a huge misjudgment.
这误会真是可太大了啊
I hope after you've graded them,
我希望你批完之后
you'll recognize
能对我有智慧的大脑
the brilliance of my brain.
存在一个清晰的认知
Fine, see you tomorrow.
好 行 明天见
Not so fast.
少安毋躁
Grade them right here, right now.
原地批阅 就地检查
You have that much confidence in yourself?
对自己这么有信心
Alright.
好
Told ya!
说什么来着
Wisdom.
智慧
Wisdom and beauty.
智慧与美
See you in the rehearsal room tomorrow.
排练室 明天见
See you tomorrow!
明天见啊
For real?
真的假的
Ling Dong is joining our band?
凌冬要加入我们乐队
No way.
不可能
I'll bet you a bag of chips
我跟你赌一包薯片
He said yes?
他真的亲口答应了
Sure!
当然
If he backs down,
他要是敢反悔
I'll just...
我就直接
Just what?
就怎么样啊
My...
大
My fellow classmate, Jinghui.
大灰灰同学
Was that necessary?
至于吗
To welcome me with such fervor.
这么热情欢迎新成员
Get your chips with this.
拿去刷
It's only through enthusiasm that
热情才能显得出
my sincerity shines through, right?
我的诚意啊 对不对
A warm welcome to our new member,
来 让我们欢迎新同学
Ling Dong.
凌冬同学加入啊
Welcome!
欢迎
Don't you
说话别再给我
let it slip!
大喘气了啊
Jinghui,
灰哥
what's Ling Dong going to play?
那凌冬玩啥啊
Good question.
问到点上了
Ling Dong won't be playing anything.
凌冬同学他什么都不玩
Ling Dong has a
凌冬同学
more important task
有更重要的使命
awaiting him.
在等着他去做
That is to use his hands
那就是用他的双手
to uphold
托起我们
the spirit of our entire band.
整个乐队的灵魂
Awesome!
好
Very good, Xiaohua, keep it up.
很好 小画 保持啊
Lan Jinghui,
兰靖灰
I won't be able to sweep.
你这样我没法扫
Then go fetch a bottle of water.
那你去拿瓶水吧
Ling Dong, I'll go.
凌冬 我去帮你
No worries, I've got it.
没事 我来
Would you like some?
你要吃吗
No!
我不吃
Open it.
拧开
I'd like some hot water.
想喝热的
Lan Jinghui,
兰靖灰
why are you ordering him around?
你干吗使唤凌冬啊
What ordering around?
这怎么能叫使唤呢
Ling Dong is
人家凌冬同学是
serving us willingly.
心甘情愿地为我们服务
As a member of the band,
作为乐队的一分子
he's in charge of
他保障着
our logistical support.
我们的后勤工作
How noble and selfless!
多么崇高 多么无私
Isn't that right, Ling Dong?
是吧 凌冬同学
You wanted it hot?
热的是吧
Just a moment.
等着
That's burning hot!
烫死了
What's the matter with you?
怎么回事你
You failed to clean the floor
地你也扫不好
and to get the water right.
水你也倒不明白
What can you actually do?
你还能干点什么
Alright, then tell me,
好 那你说
what should I do?
还要我干什么
Do you know that
那你知不知道
every school in the city
全市每一个学校
has to send a representative
都要派一个代表
to the talent competition?
去参加才艺大赛
Couldn't you go
你就不会去考察考察
and do some recon?
人家都什么节目
I need a list of their performances.
我要一个完整的节目单
Master self and foe for battle success.
知己知彼才能百战不殆
Got it.
好
He must be out of his mind.
不是 他有病吧
How can he drink water that hot?
这么热的水他能喝
You're the one who's out of your mind!
你有病吧你
Where's Ling Dong?
凌冬呢
That bookworm is slacking off again.
这个书呆子又给我摸鱼
If you keep talking like that,
你再这么说
I'll stop calling you master!
我就再也不叫你师父了
My loyal disciple,
徒弟啊
I'm merely stating the facts.
我只是陈述客观事实
You can't be too nice
像凌冬这种人
to someone like Ling Dong!
你就不能对他太好了
Right now, for all we know,
他现在指不定
he could be napping somewhere.
在哪儿睡觉呢
Wasn't it you who sent him
不是你让他去
to conduct recon?
调查情报吗
Oh, did I?
是吗
Well, he shouldn't be using up
那 那他也不能占用
our valuable rehearsal time,
我们珍贵的排练时间
right?
对不对
He could use his personal time,
他可以用休息时间嘛
What "time" are you talking about?
可以用我的什么时间
What's this?
这什么
Can't you read?
不识字啊
Summary of the talent contest programs.
才艺大赛名单汇总
Is this your work?
这是你做的
It includes each school's
连每个学校的
types of performances and the
各类表演类型
scores based on the judges' preferences
还有根据评委喜好的
from previous years.
历届评分
It's all here.
这都有
That's quite impressive!
也太牛了吧
Indeed!
确实是太厉害了
What's so impressive about this?
这有什么好夸张的
Isn't it simple?
这不很简单吗
I've also set up a WeChat group for us,
我还给大家建了一个群
to make future communication easier.
以后方便联系
A WeChat group
小群
called "Rooftop Squad." (Tian Tai Xiao Fen Dui)
群名叫天台小分队
Isn't that name a bit lame?
这也太难听了吧
Rooftop Squad?
天台小分队
Ling Dong,
凌冬
your sense for names is really off.
你这感觉也太差了吧
I think it's quite nice.
我觉得挺好的
I also think it's good.
我也觉得挺好的
'Tian' stands for Xia Qingtian.
天是夏晴天
'Xiao' is for Xiao Xiaohua.
小是肖小画
'Fen' represents Ling Dong's high scores,
分就是凌冬高分学霸
and as for 'Dui' (squad/team)...
至于队嘛
I aspire to lead the basketball team!
我想当篮球队队长
So we are
那我们就是
the Rooftop Squad.
天台小分队了
What about my name?
那我呢
Our band's formation
我们乐队的成立
also owes to the encouragement
也离不开师父你在天台
you gave me on the rooftop, master.
对我的鼓励嘛
But apprentice,
但徒弟
isn't that a bit of a stretch?
这也太牵强了吧
Though it does make some sense.
虽然也有点道理啊
Let's celebrate the formation of
那就庆祝我们
the Rooftop Squad!
天台小分队正式成立
Great!
好哎
Stop!
收
I reserve my judgment.
我持保留态度
Rooftop Squad, what kind of taste is that?
天台小分队 什么品位
No worries.
没关系
I've already experienced
你那糟糕的品位
your poor taste.
我已经领略过
Ling Dong, what do you mean by that?
凌冬 你这话什么意思
Why are you treating him like this?
你干吗 这么对凌冬
Exactly, Lan Jinghui, what do you want?
就是 兰靖灰 你要干吗
Three against one,
三个人欺负
bullying Jinghui, huh?
我家灰哥一个人是不是
Ma Yiming, you little...
马一鸣
Jinghui, hey...
灰哥 灰哥 灰哥
I didn't mean to...
灰哥 灰哥
Ma Yiming, watch it.
马一鸣你小心一点
In the long and lonely
在漫长又孤独的
school days.
校园时光里
For the first time, I felt
我第一次感受到
the warmth of a group.
集体的温暖
The Rooftop Squad is now established!
天台小分队正式成立
Grandma, I'm back.
奶奶 回来了
Jinghui, are you hungry?
小灰回来啦 饿了吧
Nope.
不饿
Grandma will make you some wontons.
奶奶给你下碗馄饨去
Grandma, I'm not hungry.
奶奶 我不饿不饿
Sit, sit.
你坐 你坐
Dad.
爸
You're not hungry? It's been a long day.
哪能不饿呢
No thanks, grandma.
不用 奶奶 奶奶
I'm really not hungry.
我真不用
I've been stuffed at school.
我今天在学校顶着了
Alright, thank you, grandma.
行行行 谢谢奶奶
I'm going upstairs, grandma.
我上楼去了 奶奶
You, look at you.
你啊 你啊 你啊
You rarely come home,
经常不回家
and when you finally do, you just...
好不容易回来一趟
Jinghui doesn't want wontons.
小灰不吃馄饨
He must be craving the noodles you make.
一定想吃你下的面
He's always been like this.
小时候就这样
Go on,
快去
make some noodles for your son.
给你儿子下碗面去 去
Later.
等会儿 等会儿
You don't do as I say?
我还说不听你了
Are you cooking or not?
去不去
Mom, mom...
妈妈妈
Sure.
去
Jinghui is at home.
小灰在家呢
Could you be considerate of my dignity?
能不能给我留点面子
Fine, off you go.
行行行 去去
Hey, Jinghui.
小灰 小灰
Stop.
停
Ma Yiming, your drumbeat was too early.
马一鸣 鼓点太早了
The rhythm was not steady.
节奏不稳
Why don't you mention Xia Qingtian
你咋不说夏晴天
is always a beat behind?
永远慢一拍呢
You have the nerve to criticize me?
你还好意思说我
It was you that messed up the flow.
本来就是你在乱弹
You can't keep up with the rhythm.
很多地方都跟不上节奏
I couldn't play in the first place.
我本来就不会
I've been trying my best!
我已经尽力了
I'm out!
不弹了
As you please.
你爱弹不弹
Stop it, both of you.
你们别吵了
It's my fault.
是我的问题
I've been a lousy singer.
我一直都唱不好
What's this?
这什么
I took some notes on the parts
我记了一下
where everyone tends to make mistakes.
大家容易出错的段落
I'm aware of the issues.
问题我都知道
I don't need you to remind me.
别跟我说这个
So it turns out I'm the one
合着就是我的问题
with the biggest issue, huh?
最大呗
Qingtian,
晴天
this is an issue for all of us,
这是我们所有人的问题
not yours alone.
不是你一个人的
Xiaohua,
小画
I know it's my problem.
我知道是我
I've been holding everyone back.
一直在拖大家后腿
Maybe you should replace me.
要不你们换一个人吧
I don't want to ruin
我也不想搞砸
your performance.
你们的演出
You're talking
你真就站着说话
from a position of comfort.
不腰疼啊
If you quit on us now,
你现在走了
how are we supposed to find a replacement?
我们去哪儿找人啊
I can give it a shot.
我可以试一下
Do you know how to play?
你会吗
Not really.
不会
If you don't, what's the point?
你不会你说啥呢
But I'm willing to learn.
但是我可以学
I'll teach you.
我教你
Come on, enlighten me, genius.
来 你告诉告诉我 天才
How many strings does a guitar have?
吉他有几根弦
Six.
六根
Good answer.
答得漂亮
He seems to be teaching a retard.
他好像在教傻子
I'll only explain once,
我只教一遍
so listen up.
你听好了啊
The thumb is for the top three strings.
大拇指管上三根
Index, middle, and ring fingers,
食指 中指 无名指
from the bottom up,
依次从下至上
are for the 1st, 2nd, and 3rd strings.
管一二三弦
Give it a try.
你试试
Relax your hand.
手放松
Strum.
弹
Do it!
弹啊
Why are you so clumsy?
怎么这么笨啊
Have you ever seen anyone play the guitar
你见过有谁弹吉他
holding it from the bottom? Try the top!
握下面的 握上面
And you're supposed to be a top student.
还三高呢
I guess I have to start from
我得从音乐幼儿启蒙课
the kindergarten level, right?
开始教你 是不是
An instrument isn't like science.
学乐器又不像学数理化
Why does Jinghui always
渣渣灰干吗老这样
talk to Ling Dong like that?
说人家凌冬
For your information,
我跟你们说
it's usually Ling Dong who tutors Jinghui.
平常都是凌冬教灰哥
Now that Jinghui finally
现在灰哥好不容易
has a chance to teach Ling Dong something,
逮着个教凌冬的机会
he must seize it and savor it.
他能不好好享受吗
I'm confident
反正我相信
Ling Dong will definitely nail it.
凌冬肯定能学会
Guys, you've worked so hard.
同学们辛苦了
Hello, Mr. Zhang!
主任好
Alright, alright.
好好好
I'm here on behalf of the school
我呢 是代表学校呢
to offer encouragement to you.
来慰问各位同学的
How's the practice coming along?
练得怎么样
Mr. Zhang, you can be assured,
主任 您放心
we, the Rooftop Squad promises
我们天台小分队
to deliver a stunning performance.
保证上场是惊艳全场
Rooftop Squad?
天台小分队
Yes, that's us.
没错
Nice name, who came up with it?
好听这名 谁起的
We thought of it together.
我们一起起的
Yes, together.
对 一起起的
Fantastic.
棒棒的
This talent competition
才艺大赛啊
really relies
这次这个活动
on all of you.
就指望大家了
Let's all put in our best effort,
一起加油 一起努力
OK?
好不好
Don't let the school down.
别让学校失望
Winning or losing isn't the main concern,
得不得成绩不重要
what matters is
重要的是
that we reflect
要体现出咱们
the spirit of Chenjun High School.
辰郡中学的精神面貌
Go for it!
加油
Yeah!
耶
Alright, I'll be heading back now.
行 那我先回去了
Goodbye, Mr. Zhang.
主任再见
Thank you, sir.
谢谢张主任
Rooftop Squad, huh?
天台小分队是吧
Who was it that was
前两天是谁在天台上
yelling on the rooftop the other day?
嚷嚷来着呀
Lan Jinghui.
兰靖灰
Why do I feel like that voice
我怎么听那个声音
sounded a lot like yours?
特别像你的声音啊
Tian, sweetie,
天儿
how come my drum is blue?
我那鼓怎么是蓝色的呀
Ma Yiming?
马一鸣
Hey, Qingtian.
不是 晴天
Why is this drum blue?
这鼓为什么是蓝色的呀
His guitar is blue too!
他的吉他也是蓝色的
His microphone is blue as well!
他的话筒也是蓝色的
Blue!
蓝色的
Here, plug this in.
来 插上这个
Blue, haha.
蓝色
Hee-hee! Blue!
蓝色 蓝色
Let's play with the drumsticks!
玩鼓锤吧
Drumsticks, drumsticks!
玩鼓锤 玩鼓锤
Yo, drumsticks.
鼓锤
It's blue.
蓝色
Qingtian, sweetie, drumsticks are so fun!
晴天我们玩鼓锤吧
Alrighty, drumsticks it is!
那 那就玩鼓锤吧
Drumsticks!
鼓锤
Drumsticks, yay!
鼓锤好嘛
Ma Yiming, are you an idiot?
马一鸣 你是傻子吗
The six elements of a triangle,
三角形的六要素
we know,
我们知道
a, b, c,
小a 小b 小c
they represent the sides.
代表的是边
A, B, C
大A 大B 大C
they represent the angles.
代表的是角
Now I'd like to ask you guys,
那我想请问一下同学们
what is the sum
大A加大B加大C
of angles A, B, and C?
等于多少度啊
Ma Yiming?
马一鸣
It's...
等于
Ling Dong, tell him.
凌冬 你告诉他
One hundred and eighty degrees.
一百八十度
Alright, let's continue.
好 我们继续啊
We know
我们知道
a, b and c represent the sides.
小a小b小c代表的是边
Then A, B...
那么大A大B
Incredible!
太厉害了
Truly a top student.
果然是三高
You pulled it off in such a short time.
这么快的时间就学会啦
Indeed.
确实
I've said it.
我就说了
Ling Dong could nail it, right?
凌冬肯定能学会吧
Thanks to my superior teaching skills!
还不是因为我教得好
No one is giving me credit.
没有人夸我
Time to eat.
吃饭去了
Feast!
干饭 干饭
Wait up.
等下我呀
This is high-end, classy, and upscale.
高端 大气 上档次啊
You all look good.
好看
"Chenjun is bound to win."
辰郡必胜
So much power.
太有力量
Just wear this for the competition.
比赛当天就穿这个上台
Sir,
主任
isn't this a bit dated?
这也太土了吧
Not at all!
土什么土啊
The principal specifically ordered,
这是校长特别叮嘱
and it's a special outfit
而且是连夜为你们
tailored for you overnight.
定制的特别舞台装
It represents
代表的是
the spirit of
咱们辰郡中学的
Chenjun High School,
一种精神面貌
a spirit of certain victory.
一种必胜的信念
You lack depth in your thinking!
什么思想境界
Go back to your practice!
排练去
My shirt doesn't have any word.
我衣服没字
He doesn't have a word.
他没字
Why doesn't Ling Dong have any word?
凌冬为什么没有字啊
He...
他
He doesn't have a word on his shirt.
不是 他的衣服没字啊
What?
什么
No word.
没字
Hmm, much better!
好多了啊
Now we are "Chenjun is bound to win!"
那我们现在就是
With an exclamation mark.
辰郡必胜 感叹号了
I'm not wearing this.
我不穿
What are you doing?
你干 你干吗
It's such a creative idea, don't waste it.
多好的创意 别浪费啊
I want yours.
我要穿你的
Hold on.
稍安勿躁
If you really want to change it,
如果你一定要穿的话
I'll find another one for you.
我帮你再找一件
Ma Yiming,
马一鸣
take yours off and give it to him.
把你的脱了给他
Forget it!
我不
Ling Dong, let's take his off.
凌冬 咱俩脱他的
Stop, stop!
停 停
Have you ever seen
你曾经看过
the things of Los Angeles at 4 a.m.?
凌晨4点的洛杉矶吗
Hey, bro, now it's only 11pm.
现在只有11点 兄弟
I'm trying to capture that atmosphere.
哥就表达那种意境
Are we going or not? Go home?
走不走 回家
Right away.
我就走